# YONG SHENG TAN

in /tanys

**■** i@yong.space **□** 9753 · 6644

Financial technology professional with 11+ years of experience across software development, business analysis and production support looking to further career in a technical or product/platform development role. Adept in managing software delivery lifecycles with a keen understanding of enterprise systems and cloud architecture.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Orkes Jan 2024 - Present

Senior Solutions Architect

- Launched APAC office tasked with establishing regional presence for sales, consulting, developer relations
- Led pre-sales engineering, technical account management and solutions architecture for non-US customers
- Responsible for technical customer success in converting platform investment into realised business value
- Organised developer meet-up events and presented at key business and technical conferences regionally

### Symphony Communications

Feb 2019 - Jan 2024

Manager, Developer Solutions

- Led engineering team that delivers Symphony's suite of developer tools for building bots and integrations
- Responsible for product roadmap, backlog grooming, delivery management and customer engagement
- Bridged customer domains with technical requirements to ensure developer tools were fit-for-purpose
- Delivered greenfield workflow studio product that facilitates non-developers in building workflows
- Liaised with FINOS to maintain standards of open source project delivery and community contributions

## Developer Relations Technical Lead

- Pioneering lead of team tasked to scale engagement and education of Symphony's developer community
- Subject matter expert on best practices for using developer tools to build solutions for markets use-cases
- Built certification program from scratch, comprising course material, demos, videos, exams and badges
- Developed and ran assets including a developer portal, training center, forum and documentation site
- Organised global events like developer meetups, hackathons, webinars and Innovate conferences

GIC Jun 2016 - Feb 2019

Engineering Lead, Enterprise Applications Technology

- Led engineering on a new cross-asset CRM platform that pioneered use of cloud-native architecture
- Responsible for scoping requirements, delivery, deployments, support and managing team of developers
- Key developer on innovation award-winning platform for sharing investment ideas across asset classes

## Developer, Public Equities Analytics

- Built Tableau dashboards visualising portfolio exposure, performance and facets for public equities teams
- Led development of equities data mart, designing the structure and ETL workflows in Informatica
- Optimised performance of dashboards through tuning of Oracle databases and batch automation

NatWest Markets Sep 2013 – Mar 2016

Support Analyst, Sales and Trading Analytics

- Provided regional production support for the business intelligence suite used by sales and trading desks
- Responsible for coverage mappings that ensure accurate distribution and reporting of sales income flows
- Built data visualisation dashboards that enabled decision analysis for the APAC wind down programme

# Business Analyst, Market Risk Technology

- Managed delivery of in-house market risk platform, liaising with risk managers and engineering
- Mitigated impact to risk sensitivity and VaR metrics from upstream changes through tolerance analysis
- Developed an interactive guide that highlights relationships of sensitivities used to risk manage products

#### Developer, Operations Technology

- Developed VBA-based tools for operations teams to enable reconciliation, clearing, reporting functions
- Pioneered usage of Python to facilitate straight-through reconciliation of counterparty settlement data

#### **EDUCATION**

# Singapore Management University

Aug 2009 - Jul 2013

BSc (Information Systems Management), summa cum laude

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Certified Kubernetes Application Developer, VMware Spring Professional 2021, Oracle Java Professional